# HASNAIN UD DIN BILAL.

Email: hasnainbilal.fazaian@gmail.com

Contact: +971 522047116 Address: Dubai, UAE

LinkedIn Profile: linkedin.com/in/hasnain-uddin-bilal-274b8318b/

GitHub Profile: github.com/hasnainbilal

Visa Status: Visit (3 Months) | December – February



## **Full Stack Web Developer**

I am a dedicated and efficient full-stack web developer with more than three years of experience in building SaaS applications in agile environments. My experience involves building scalable web applications using Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery, and core PHP. I had developed and integrated APIs for mobile applications running on android and IOS. I am able to design database schema and provide the best and most efficient solution to client requirements.

## **Education**

2015-2019 - BSc Software Engineering from University of Engineering and Technology Peshawar with CGPA of 3.54/4.

2014-2015 – Studied Additional Mathematics from Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education with A+ Grade.

2012-2013 - Completed HSSC from Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education in Pre-Medical with Grade A.

2011-2012 - Completed SSC from Federal Board of Intermediate and Secondary Education in Science with Grade A+.

#### **Skills**

Front End Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript Back End Languages: PHP, Python

Frameworks: Laravel, Bootstrap Libraries: ¡Query, React

**Databases:** MySQL, Mongo **Tools:** Sublime Text, VS Code, Dreamweaver, Android Studio

## **Work History**

#### **Computer Programmer at Be Relax**

23<sup>rd</sup> February 2022 - Till Date

Dubai, UAE

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Integration of user-facing elements according to company requirements.
- Build efficient, testable, and reusable PHP modules.
- Solve complex performance problems and architectural challenges.
- Maintain the company's current software, and website.
- Enhance the company's mobile application (IOS and Android) in design and performance.
- Managing the updates in the content and upgrading the database accordingly.

#### Web Engineer at Veevo Tech

1<sup>st</sup> December 2020 – 30th November 2021

Peshawar, Pakistan

## **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data visually.
- Created APIs for new software and Mobile Applications.
- Converted existing website's design to new design.
- Integrated third party APIs into current software.
- Liaised with back-end developers, front end developers, quality assurance testers, and CTO as needed.
- Managed time-sensitive updates, including content changes and database upgrades

#### IT Engineer at ABNB Technical Services L.L.C (remote)

3<sup>rd</sup> August 2020 – 30<sup>th</sup> Oct 2021

Dubai, UAE

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Work as a part-time web developer and manage the company website.
- Integrate external APIs to the current website of the company.
- Update the content on the website according to the company's requirements.
- Provide IT Support to the Staff.
- Train employees on new software.

### **Junior Web Developer at Quinin Technologies**

13 January 2020 – 17 March 2020

Peshawar, Pakistan

#### **Key Qualifications & Responsibilities**

- Maximized applications' efficiency, data quality, scope, operability, and flexibility.
- Managed, optimized, and updated PHP databases as necessary.

## Intern at Pakhtunkhwa Energy Development Organization

2 August 2019 – 30 November 2019

Swat Bahrain, Pakistan

## **Job Description**

Working with different experienced Engineers and maintain the operation and control of power plant Through SCADA.

#### **Freelancer at Fiverr**

February 2018 - Till Date

Level 2 Seller

www.fiverr.com/bangash2211

## **Job Description**

- Design responsive websites in WordPress
- Fix bugs and issues related to PHP
- Design PowerPoint Slides, Edit and create fillable PDF
- · Edit videos and create videos using filmora
- Assist in MS Excel Tasks
- Design banners in Photoshop

#### **Final Year Project**

May 2018 – June 2019

Developed a renting website

#### **Project Description**

Created a web-based rental and reselling platform where people meet to get branded items at an affordable price. People can put their accessories from their branded shirts, pants, shoes, and watches to their wedding dresses, and even their electronic devices like cameras, speakers, etc. for rent. Besides this one can also resale their items if they no more need them.

#### Technology

The front-end was designed in bootstrap while the back-end was created in Laravel. The server used was Apache and the database was MySQL. It was hosted in a virtual environment.

## **Academics Honor**

- Shaheen Merit Certificate awarded in 2009.
- Shaheen Merit Certificate awarded in 2011.
- Fazaia Certificate of Merit awarded in 2012.
- Final Year Project Exhibition Certificate awarded in 2019.

## **Personality Traits**

- Solution Focused
- Innovative
- Team Work Ability
- Task Oriented
- Good Communication Skills
- Good Presentation Skills